Guide to the Douglas Killgore video materials, 1911-2013 UA 405
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Douglas Killgore video materials
1911-2013
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Killgore, Douglas
UA 405
7 Linear Feet 7 boxes
4.6 Gigabytes Nearline archival information package UA0405aip_001, containing digital video files of the 1993 film, "The Trust"
The collection contains audio-visual material created and edited by Douglas Killgore during his time at Rice University, both as a student in the 1970s and, decades later, as an independent filmmaker. The materials document people and events at Rice and the history of the university from 1911-2013.
Biographical / Historical
Doug Killgore (1947- ), a Louisiana native, turned an early interest in film, television, and the space program into a long, productive career. In 1965, still in high school, one of his films won honorable mention in a national contest and was part of his application to Rice. On the way to earning two degrees ('70, '71), he acted in numerous productions and continued to film — notably "The Great Dogfight," "Grigsby G," and weekly TV spots called "Rice News on Campus." After service in Vietnam, he worked at Theater Under the Stars, earned a master's degree in film, and established Killgore Productions, with Rice as one of his clients. James Morehead's "Walking Tour" and a feature film, "The Trust," were among his notable Rice-related successes. He owned and operated The Woodlands Science and Art Center before returning to Rice, where he shot and edited a wide variety of videos and films, 2004-2014.
Scope and Contents
Seven boxes of audio and film reels, VHS and Beta video cassettes, mini-cassettes, compact discs, and DVDs created by Douglas Killgore document the history of Rice University from 1911-2013. Of particular interest is Killgore Productions' film, "The Trust: The Story of the Murder of William Marsh Rice" and the complete 1996 Nobel Prize in Chemistry presentation, with that year's recipients: Robert Curl, Harold Kroto, and Richard Smalley.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586. Allow 24 hours retrieval time.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials for this collection were donated by Douglas Killgore.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged in one series and in chronological order at item level.
Index Terms
Subjects
Rice University -- History; Universities and colleges
Document Types
digital moving image formats; videotapes; audiotapes; compact discs
- Series I: Media
  - Dorothy Weiser Seale footage from 1930s Rice scenes, Killgore, (DVCAM) (Box 1)
  - Dorothy Weiser Seale, Rice 1930s, (DV) (Box 1)
  - Dorothy Weiser Seale / Scenes of Rice, 1937, including graduation, Rice Media, (DVD), 2005-10 (Box 1)
  - 1937 and 1939 campus scenes, from Dorothy Weiser Seale '37 and William W. Seale '39 (2), (VHS), 1937-1944 (Box 1)
  - Rice 16mm Archival Film Footage, (DVD), 1940 (Box 1)
  - Fondren Through the Years: An Oral History, Fondren Oral History, (DVD), 1949-2006 (Box 1)
  - Rice Inaugural Ceremonies (Pitzer), Killgore, (DVD), 1950 (Box 1)
  - Rice '51 close-ups, (DV), 2001 (Box 1)
  - Through the Sallyport: Rice Film, 1950s (2), Killgore, (DVD) (Box 1)
  - Through the Sallyport, 1950s, (DVCAM) (Box 1)
  - Rice Football Highlights, 1953 SW Conference Co-champs, (DVD) (Box 1)
  - Rice on Film, Vol. 1: Thru the Sallyport, Golden Years, Morehead Walking Tour, Rice Today, Charter Centennial, Data DVD, Rice Media, (DVD), 1953-1991 (Box 1)
  - Rice on film, Vols. 1-2: Thru Sallyport, Golden Yrs, Walking Tour, Rice Today, Charter Centennial; Leading New Century, Social Sciences 25th anniv., Small is Big, Lovett to Leebron (3), Rice IT, (DVD), 1953-2005 (Box 1)
  - Rice Men's Glee Club, 1954; "Rice's Honor" and "Sammy O!", (DV) (Box 1)
  - In the Name of Peace; Face the Nation with Dudley Sharp (2), Fondren Library 16mm film, (DVD), 1960 (Box 1)
  - Rice Computer, 1960s, 1 of 2, (DV) (Box 1)
  - Rice 1960s 8mm movie clips (2), Rice Media, (DVD) (Box 1)
  - "Rice University Inaugural Ceremonies" Kinescope Recording, Part 2, (film), 1960 (Box 1)
  - Rice in the '60s, Greased Pole, Beer-Bike, Power Puff, Killgore, (film), 1960 (Box 1)
  - Rice Computer 1961 TV Program (4), Rice Media, (DVD) (Box 1)
  - Completed Computer, Kinescope Recording, (film), 1961 (Box 1)
  - Completed Computer / Martin Graham, (Betamax), 1961 (Box 1)
  - Pitzer Inauguration; Graham film, Engineering recruiting video, (DVCAM), 1961 (Box 1)
  - Pitzer Inauguration; G. R. Brown; Dr. Houston off camera, (DVCAM), 1961 (Box 1)
  - Completed Computer, (VHS), 1961 (Box 1)
  - Golden Years (3), Killgore, (DVD), 1962 (Box 1)
  - Golden Years, (DVCAM), 1962 (Box 1)
  - JFKennedy Talk Orig Version, Rice U Media Services, (DVD), 1962 (Box 1)
  - Golden Years, Print #2, (film), 1962 (Box 1)
  - Why the moon? JFK, Rice U Media Services, (DVD), 1962 (Box 1)
  - Address on Nation's Space Effort/ JFK, Kennedy Presidential Library, (dvd), 1962-09-12 (Box 1)
  - JFK at Rice University - 1962, Zenfilm, (DVD), 2009-07-12 (Box 1)
  - We Will Go to the Moon/ JFK (3), Rice IT, (DVD), 1962-09-12 (Box 1)
  - John F. Kennedy - "Why Go to the Moon?, Rice U EdTech, (DVD), 1962-09-21 (Box 1)
  - Rice on film, Vol. 3, 1962-1995: Why Go to the Moon?; 80 yrs of Athletics; honoring Barnetts; McMurtry College ground break; TV spots (7), Rice IT, (DVD), 2007 (Box 1)
  - History of Rice IT, 1964-72, (DVD), 1964-1972 (Box 1)
  - 8mm footage: Greased Pole Climb, Beer-Bike, ROTC ceremony (5), Killgore, (DVD), 1965-1970 (Box 1)
  - Great Dogfight, Wiess College, 1967 (5), (DVD) (Box 1)
  - The Great Dogfight (Wiess College, 1967) and Small is Big, Rice Media, (DVD), 1967-2005 (Box 1)
  - Great Dogfight, Various 8mm Rice scenes, (DV), 1968-04-01 (Box 1)
  - Hackerman Inauguration, (film), 1970 (Box 1)
  - Grigsby G (4), Rice Media, (DVD), 1970 (Box 1)
  - Brochman Physics Bldg dedication, (DV), 1971-03-24 (Box 1)
  - Rice's First Computer, (film), 1971-05-25 (Box 1)
  - Rices First Computer, Killgore Productions, (DVD), 1971-05-25 (Box 1)
  - History of Rice IT, Mini-movies, 1972-, (DVD) (Box 1)
  - Homecoming 50th Reunion, (film), 1975 (Box 1)
  - Rice Today 1977 backup files, Rice Media, (DVD) (Box 1)
  - Rice on film volume 1, early version, (DVD), 1977 (Box 1)
  - Rice Today 1977, (DV) (Box 1)
  - Rice Today - 1977 slide show, (DV) (Box 1)
  - Rice on Film, Vol. 2: Rice Today, Leading the New Century, Social Sciences 25th anniv., Small is Big, Lovett to Leebron (7), (DVD), 1977-2005 (Box 1)
  - Selected Projects: Walking Tour, Rice Today, TV spots, Hudspeth at Homecoming, Centennial (1991), The Trust trailer (2), Killgore, (DVD), 1979-1993 (Box 1)
  - Geoff Winningham / Game Day (2), Rice IT, (DVD), 1982 (Box 1)
  - Geoff Winningham / Game Day, (DV), 1982 (Box 1)
  - Rice Today 1984, (DVD) (Box 1)
  - Harris Masterson interview / Karen Rogers, (DV), 1985-11 (Box 1)
  - Malcolm Lovett; Herbert Allen, (audio reel), 1985-12-20 (Box 1)
  - Old Rice Spot, (DV), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Rice Fundamental, 1987, "Found on Desk", (DV) (Box 1)
  - The Light Stuff Daedulus, (DVD), 1988 (Box 1)
  - Rice Today: A Walking Tour; The Last of the Little Breweries, Pearlman, (VHS), 1988-08-08 (Box 1)
  - "In Hope of High Achievement", Pearlman, (VHS), 1988-08-09 (Box 1)
  - Through the Sallyport: Rice Film, 1950s, (VHS), 1988-11-28 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Profiles, 1989 and Rice Athletics 80 years, (DVD) (Box 1)
  - Malcolm Lovett interview, (DVD), 1989 (Box 1)
  - Tribute to H. Malcolm Lovett (2), (DVD), 1989-05-25 (Box 1)
  - Dell Butcher Hall Dedication, (VHS), 1989 (Box 2)
  - H. Malcolm Lovett / interviewed by John B. Boles (3), Killgore, (VHS), 1989-05-25 (Box 2)
  - H. Malcolm Lovett / interviewed by John B. Boles (4), one labeled "Dub", Killgore, (VHS), 1989-06-01 (Box 2)
  - Hank Hudspeth / Address at Homecoming, Killgore, (VHS), 1990 (Box 2)
  - Baker Institute Video, (DV), 1990 (Box 2)
  - For Rice's Honor - Athletic Awards/History Stone Films, (DV), 1990 (Box 2)
  - Commencement, (VHS), 1991 (Box 2)
  - Views of Campus Archival Footage, (DV), 1991 (Box 2)
  - Letters, Science and Art, Charter Centennial video, (DV), 1991 (Box 2)
  - Rice University: Letters, Science and Art, Killgore, (VHS), 1991 (Box 2)
  - Rice University Backup Data: Centennial Celebration, (DVD), 1991 (Box 2)
  - Richard Smalley B-Roll Footage, (VHS), 1992-10-08 (Box 2)
  - The Trust (2), Killgore, (DVD), 1993 (Box 2)
  - Tribute to H. Malcolm Lovett, (VHS), 1993-04-03 (Box 2)
  - Eighty Years of Rice Athletics, (VHS), 1994 (Box 2)
  - Baker Institute Groundbreaking, Rice IT, (DVD), 1994-10-20 (Box 2)
  - Baker Institute Groundbreaking, (VHS), 1994-10-20 (Box 2)
  - Nobel Prize award, (VHS), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Nobel Prize award, (VHS), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Nobel Prize award, (VHS), 1996 (Box 2)
  - 1996 Nobel Prize footage: Smalley, Curl, Kroto, Rice; EdTech, (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Social Sciences 25th anniversary--Final Edit, (DV), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Social Sciences 25th anniversary--Leeds, Long, Klineberg, Lane, (DV), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Nobel Footage: Curl, Smalley + Stockholm, (DV), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Visit with Harris Masterson (2), Rice IT, (VHS), 1996-04 (Box 2)
  - Visit with Harris Masterson, Rice IT, (DVD), 1996-04 (Box 2)
  - Harris Masterson interview / Karen Rogers, Rice Media, (VHS), 1996-04-19 (Box 2)
  - Glenwood Tour #1, (DV), 1996-10 (Box 2)
  - Glenwood Tour #2, (DV), 1996-10 (Box 2)
  - Glenwood Inserts, (DV), 1996-10 (Box 2)
  - Stephen Fox tour, (DVD), 1997 (Box 2)
  - Helen Mims ('20); interview by Doug Killgore, Rice U Bands, (DV), 1997 (Box 2)
  - Ezra Charles #1, (DV), 1997-01-18 (Box 2)
  - History of Black Students at Rice / Karen Kosse (2), (VHS), 1997-02-09 (Box 2)
  - Karen Kosse, History of Blacks at Rice #1, (DV), 1997-02-09 (Box 2)
  - Karen Kosse, History of Blacks at Rice #2, (DV), 1997-02-09 (Box 2)
  - Stephen Fox / Rice Tour #1, (DV), 1997-03-08 (Box 2)
  - Stephen Fox / Rice Tour #2, (DV), 1997-03-08 (Box 2)
  - Interview with David Parsons (2), (VHS), 1997-04-30 (Box 2)
  - Catherine Hannah; H. Dyer, (DV), 1997-06 (Box 2)
  - Franz Brotzen; interview by Melissa Kean, RHS, (DV), 1997-08-02 (Box 2)
  - Ken Dye party #1, (DV), 1997-08-09 (Box 2)
  - Tom Eubank #1, (DV), 1998-01-20 (Box 2)
  - Tom Eubank #2, (DV), 1998-01-20 (Box 2)
  - Rice/NASA signing ceremony raw footage, (VHS), 1998-10-15 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1948 50th Reunion, (VHS) 1998-11-13/1998-11-14 (Box 2)
  - Malcolm Gillis Alumni Address, typed label, (VHS), 1999-01 (Box 2)
  - Malcolm Gillis Alumni Address, (DV), 1999-01-29 (Box 2)
  - Al Jensen and Milton McGinty, Rice Stadium, (DV), 1999-02-25 (Box 2)
  - RHS, Malcolm McCants, (DV), 1999-03-25 (Box 2)
  - Katherine Brown; Neal Heaps, (DV), 1999-04-22 (Box 2)
  - Bremen Stock, (DV), 1999-09-02 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1949 50th Reunion, (VHS) 1999-11-12/1999-11-13 (Box 2)
  - "Mary Hale Lovett?", (DV), 2000-01-27 (Box 2)
  - Gillis matriculation, (DV), 2000-08-20 (Box 2)
  - Matusau interviews 2, (DV), 2000-08-27 (Box 2)
  - Boles on Lovett, (DV), 2000-11-03 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1950 50th Reunion, (VHS) 2000-11-03/2000-11-04 (Box 3)
  - G. Mitchell; N. Hackerman, (DV), 2000-12-14 (Box 2)
  - Malcolm Gillis, State of the University, Rice Hotel, (DV), 2000-01-25 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Curl, Killgore, (DVD), 2000-04-10 (Box 3)
  - Neil Havens, A Man for All Seasons, Rice IT, (VHS), 2000-04-14 (Box 3)
  - The Cain Project, (DV), 2001-01 (Box 2)
  - Lovett Hall, 1911-2011, Rice Media Services, (DVD), 2001-03-20 (Box 2)
  - Malcolm Gillis Matriculation Address, (VHS), 2001-08-19 (Box 3)
  - Rice matriculation #1, (DV), 2001-08-19 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Lecture O-week, (DV), 2001-08-20 (Box 3)
  - Louis Girard #1, (DV), 2001-10-30 (Box 3)
  - Louis Girard #2, (DV), 2001-10-30 (Box 3)
  - Rice '51 #1, (DVCam), 2001-11-09 (Box 3)
  - Hello, Hamlet!, (VHS), 2002 (Box 3)
  - Red Bale interview, (DVD), 2002-05 (Box 3)
  - 89th Commencement (Graduate), (DVD), 2002-05-11 (Box 3)
  - Red Bale #1, (DV), 2002-05-23 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Lecture, (DV), 2002-08-29 (Box 3)
  - Calvin Class interviewed by Melissa Kean, (DVD), 2002-10-24 (Box 3)
  - Calvin Class #1 of 2, (DV), 2002-10-24 (Box 3)
  - Calvin Class #2, (DV), 2002-10-24 (Box 3)
  - DOC class 1 of 2 (2), (DV), 2002-10-24 (Box 3)
  - DOC class 2 of 2 (2), (DV), 2002-10-24 (Box 3)
  - Ray Watkin Hoagland Strange / conversation (2), (DVD), 2003 (Box 3)
  - Malcolm Gillis Matriculation Address, Rice IT, (DVD), 2003 (Box 3)
  - Rice College World Series Rally, (DV), 2003 (Box 2)
  - Merissa Leebron and College World Series Rally, (DV), 2003 (Box 3)
  - Nano birthday party, 2 of 2, (DV), 2003 (Box 3)
  - Bridging the Gap: Policy and Research / honoring Neal Lane, (DVD), 2003 (Box 2)
  - Rice #10: Claire Bartlett; Steven Currall, (DVCAM), 2003 (Box 2)
  - Rice Leading New Century - Keep! [Most Important Historical], (DVCAM), 2003 (Box 2)
  - Ranks of Rice Films, Audio, (DV), 2003-03-12 (Box 3)
  - Rice #1, (DVCAM), 2003-08-14 (Box 2)
  - Rice #2, (DVCAM), 2003-08-17 (Box 2)
  - Rice #6: Graham, Owl's Eye View, (DVCAM), 2003-08-20 (Box 2)
  - Rice #5: B-roll; Dean Whitaker; Jones School, (DVCAM), 2003-08-21 (Box 2)
  - Rice #8: Lars Lerup; Baseball party, RMC, (DVCAM), 2003-08-26 (Box 2)
  - Rick at SOL, (DVD), 2003-09 (Box 2)
  - Wiess College Dedication--student, (DV), 2003-10-05 (Box 2)
  - Riki Kobayaski retirement #1, (DV), 2003-10-10 (Box 3)
  - Riki Kobayaski retirement #2, (DV), 2003-10-10 (Box 3)
  - Bridging the Gap, session 9, (DVD), 2003-11-02 (Box 2)
  - Bridging the Gap: Dr. Richard Smalley (2), (DVD), 2003-11-02 (Box 2)
  - Modeling / Air Quality in Houston, (DVD), 2003-11-04 (Box 2)
  - Nano Celebration, (DVD), 2003-11-13 (Box 3)
  - Nano Dinner, (DV), 2003-11-13 (Box 3)
  - MOB video by Will Price, includes "Louie, Louie", (DV), 2004 (Box 3)
  - O-Week Skits, Tape 2, (DV), 2004 (Box 3)
  - 50 Year Reunion, Class of 1954, (DVD), 2004 (Box 4)
  - Stock Scenes of Rice, (DV), 2004 (Box 4)
  - Gillis Retirement Video, (DV), 2004 (Box 3)
  - Decision 2004, (VHS) (Box 4)
  - David Leebron Inauguration, (DVD), 2004 (Box 4)
  - SCIENTIA: Robert Curl / Will Humanity Survive?, (DV), 2004-01-02 (Box 3)
  - Raymond Johnson, (DV), 2004-02-09 (Box 3)
  - Social Sciences 25th anniversary--Susan McIntosh, (DV), 2004-02-16 (Box 3)
  - Robert J. Samuelson / Secret History of Inflation, (DV), 2004-02-17 (Box 3)
  - Robert Hulbert / Potable Water Quality (2), (DVD), 2004-02-24 (Box 4)
  - Paul Avery / Data Grids, CITI Lecture #1 of 2, (DV), 2004-03-08 (Box 3)
  - Paul Avery / Data Grids, CITI Lecture #2 of 2, (DV), 2004-03-08 (Box 3)
  - Larry Soward / Coastal and Surface Water Quality (2), (DVD), 2004-03-11 (Box 4)
  - Michael Carroll / Hot Bats are Too Hot to Handle, Rice, (DVD), 2004-03-18 (Box 4)
  - Flooding and Watershed Management, Rice, (DVD), 2004-03-23 (Box 4)
  - Gillis testimonial, (DV), 2004-03-24 (Box 3)
  - Gillis testimonial, (DV), 2004-03-24 (Box 3)
  - Bye, Bye, Gillis, (DV), 2004-03-24 (Box 3)
  - Charles Duncan, (DV), 2004-03-25 (Box 3)
  - Bucky Allshouse, (DV), 2004-03-26 (Box 3)
  - Jim C[rownover], Mrs. G[illis], Doug K -- luncheon, (DV), 2004-03-30 (Box 3)
  - Peggy and Bill Barnett, (DV), 2004-04-01 (Box 3)
  - FotoFest 2004, Part 1 State of Water in the World / Lane, Postel, Auerbach (13), Global Forum on Water, (DVD) 2004-04-01/2004-04-04 (Box 4)
  - Fotofest 2004, Part 2 State of Water in the World / Djerejan, Priscoli, Global Forum on Water, (DVD) 2004-04-01/2004-04-04 (Box 4)
  - Fotofest 2004, Part 3 Texas as a Microcosm / Rose, Kelly, Blackburn (4), Global Forum on Water, (DVD) 2004-04-01/2004-04-04 (Box 4)
  - Fotofest 2004, Part 4 Lessons from Global Change / Dunbar, Jackson, Sorooshian (4), Global Forum on Water, (DVD) 2004-04-01/2004-04-04 (Box 4)
  - Fotofest 2004 Part 5 Re-Visioning Water, The Future / Barlow, Pryne, QandA (4), Global Forum on Water, (DVD) 2004-04-01/2004-04-04 (Box 4)
  - Fotofest 2004 Part 7 Re-Visioning Water, Technology ? Wiesner, Hughes, Stapleton, QandA (5), Global Forum on Water, (DVD) 2004-04-01/2004-04-04 (Box 4)
  - Fotofest 2004 Part 8 Re-Visioning Water, Looking Forward / Lester, Auerbach, Dreiseitl, Stapleton, Lane (2), Global Forum on Water, (DVD) 2004-04-01/2004-04-04 (Box 4)
  - Brian Riedel #1 Wide, (DV), 2004-04-02 (Box 3)
  - McNair CORROA, (DV), 2004-04-06 (Box 3)
  - President Gillis Tells It Like It Was; interviewed by John Boles (3), Rice Digital Media; interview by J. B. Boles, (DVD), 2004-04-13-2004-04-14 (Box 4)
  - Boles / Gillis, Day 1, (DV), 2004-04-14 (Box 3)
  - Boles / Gillis, Day 2, (DV), 2004-04-14 (Box 3)
  - Elizabeth and Malcolm Gillis testimonial video (5), (DVD), 2004-04-24 (Box 4)
  - Owls Rule; Malcolm and Elizabeth Gillis Tribute (6), Rice Digital Media, (DVD), 2004-04-24 (Box 4)
  - Rice DMS: Celebrate Helen [Havens], St. Stephen's Church, (DV), 2004-05-08 (Box 3)
  - Lehmann Symposium, Part 5 (2), Rice, (DVD), 2004-05-20 (Box 4)
  - Lehmann Symposium, Part 6, (DVD), 2004-05-20 (Box 4)
  - Lehmann Symposium, Part 8, (DVD), 2004-05-21 (Box 4)
  - Lehmann Symposium, (DVD), 2004-05-21 (Box 4)
  - Wyman Miles, Tape 1, (DV), 2004-07-19 (Box 3)
  - Wyman Miles, Tape 2, (DV), 2004-07-19 (Box 3)
  - Matriculation for Class of 2008 (2), Rice Digital Media, (DVD), 2004-08-15 (Box 4)
  - Rice DMS: David Leebron's first matriculation, (DV), 2004-08-15 (Box 3)
  - Rice DMS: Faculty address--Lynne Huffer, (DV), 2004-08-16 (Box 3)
  - End of Berlin Airlift, (DV), 2004-09 (Box 3)
  - Rice DMS: Shots of Princeton and Columbia, (DV), 2004-09-01 (Box 3)
  - George Rupp interview, IRC office, New York, (DV), 2004-09-03 (Box 3)
  - Rice DMS: George Rupp Interview, IRC, re Leebron, (DV), 2004-09-03 (Box 3)
  - Rice DMS: Leebron conversation with Dallas alumni, (DV), 2004-09-09 (Box 3)
  - Conversation with the President [Leebron] (2), Rice Digital Media, (DVD), 2004-09-09 (Box 4)
  - Rice DMS: "For Rice's Honor" #1, (DV), 2004-09-12 (Box 3)
  - Rice DMS: "For Rice's Honor" #2, (DV), 2004-09-12 (Box 3)
  - Spinning Nanotube Fibers, Rice, (DVD), 2004-09-16 (Box 3)
  - Spinning Nanotubes Lab #1, (DV), 2004-09-16 (Box 3)
  - Spinning Nanotubes Lab #2, (DV), 2004-09-16 (Box 3)
  - Internet 2 broadcast Shepherd School #1, (DV), 2004-09-27 (Box 3)
  - Rice DMS: Internet 2 Demo #2, Brian Connelly piano, (DV), 2004-09-27 (Box 3)
  - David Leebron Investiture, (DV), 2004-10 (Box 3)
  - David Leebron inaugural dinner, (DV), 2004-10-01 (Box 3)
  - Rice DMS: Leebron Inauguration Summons, Camera 1, (DV), 2004-10-01 (Box 3)
  - Rice DMS: Leebron Inauguration Summons, Camera 2, (DV), 2004-10-01 (Box 3)
  - Leebron Investiture Ceremony, Rice IT, (DVD), 2004-10-02 (Box 4)
  - David Leebron inaugural dinner, (DV), 2004-10-02 (Box 3)
  - Leebron inaugural functions--Mayor, Leebron, (DV), 2004-10-02 (Box 3)
  - Sidney Burrus on Duncan Hall, (DV), 2004-10-03 (Box 3)
  - Houston Air Quality, part 1, (DVD), 2004-10-06 (Box 4)
  - Keith Cooper on Duncan Hall, (DV), 2004-10-08 (Box 3)
  - Rice Alliance lunch, (DV), 2004-10-14 (Box 3)
  - Rice Alliance L #2, (DV), 2004-10-14 (Box 3)
  - Chris Holmes interview, Shell Sustainability Center, (DV), 2004-10-15 (Box 3)
  - Richard Baraniuk interview, (DV), 2004-11-02 (Box 3)
  - Social Sciences 25th anniversary--Ron Soligo, (DV), 2004-11-23 (Box 3)
  - Lovett Hall exteriors, with azaleas and without, (DV), 2004-2005 (Box 3)
  - Admissions Video, Campus and Students, (DV), 2004-2005 (Box 3)
  - Admissions Video, Campus, (DV), 2004-2005 (Box 3)
  - Admissions Video, Students, (DV), 2004-2005 (Box 3)
  - Campus stock footage; [2005] Admissions Video; [2004]Leading the New Century, Rice IT, (DVD), 2004-2005 (Box 4)
  - Rice Stock Footage: [2005-6]Campus Stock Footage; [2005] Admissions Video; [2004] Leading the New Century (2), Rice IT, (DVD), 2004-2006 (Box 4)
  - Rice Circus; Gottschalk for Killgore, (DVD), 2005 (Box 3)
  - Ping Sun, Leebron avi files, clips, Chinese delegation, (DVD), 2005 (Box 3)
  - Guinness Nanotube, Small is Big, (DV), 2005 (Box 3)
  - Sid Rich Students, (DV), 2005 (Box 6)
  - Flamingos video, (DV), 2005 (Box 3)
  - Rick Smalley Slide Show (2), (DVD), 2005 (Box 4)
  - Ethnic Houston 2005 Video Class, (DVD) (Box 3)
  - Martel College Groundbreaking; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005 (Box 4)
  - John Boles / Lovett to Leebron, (DV), 2005 (Box 3)
  - Lovett to Leebron, show tape finished, (DV), 2005 (Box 3)
  - Social Sciences 25th anniversary--Cuthbertson, Zodrow, Martin, (DV), 2005-01 (Box 3)
  - 25th Anniversary Video Rough-cut and Final, Rice Digital Media, (DVD), 2005-01-05 (Box 4)
  - Nano Games, Roush backup, (DV), 2005-01-05 (Box 3)
  - Social Sciences 25th Anniversary Celebration (3), Rice Digital Media, (DVD), 2005-01-05 (Box 4)
  - Celebrating the Life of Frank E. Vandiver (4), Rice Digital Media, (DVD), 2005-01-11 (Box 4)
  - Frank Vandiver memorial service, (DV), 2005-01-11 (Box 3)
  - Wellness Tour, (DV), 2005-01-26 (Box 3)
  - Matriculation, 2 of 2, (DV), 2005-02-05 (Box 3)
  - Douglas Greenberg / Henry's Harmonica: Memory and History in a Genocidal World (2), Rice IT, (DVD), 2005-02-10 (Box 3)
  - Malcolm Gillis; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-02-10 (Box 3)
  - SHOAH Footage McMurtry, (DV), 2005-02-10 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Jones (former Dean) interview, (DV), 2005-02-11 (Box 3)
  - Raymond Brochstein; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-02-21 (Box 3)
  - Edward Djerejian; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-02-22 (Box 3)
  - Elizabeth Gillis; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-02-23 (Box 3)
  - EESI Conference, 1 of 7, (DV), 2005-02-24 (Box 3)
  - EESI Conference, 2 of 7, (DV), 2005-02-24 (Box 3)
  - EESI Conference, 3 of 7, (DV), 2005-02-24 (Box 3)
  - EESI Conference, 4 of 7, (DV), 2005-02-24 (Box 3)
  - EESI Conference, 6 of 7, (DV), 2005-02-24 (Box 3)
  - EESI Conference, 7 of 7, (DV), 2005-02-24 (Box 3)
  - EESI Conference, Tape 4, (DV), 2005-02-24 (Box 3)
  - Jack Blanton; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-02-25 (Box 3)
  - Gil Whitaker; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-03-09 (Box 3)
  - IT meets IT Party, (DV), 2005-03-10 (Box 3)
  - Jim Crownover; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-03-14 (Box 3)
  - James A. Baker III / Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-03-15 (Box 3)
  - Stephen Klineberg on EESI and Houston Survey, (DV), 2005-03-21 (Box 3)
  - Charles Duncan; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-03-22 (Box 3)
  - Rebecca Richards-Kortum / Microarrays, Rice Media, (DVD), 2005-03-22 (Box 3)
  - Kathleen Matthews; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-03-28 (Box 3)
  - Amory Lovins / Winning the Oil Endgame, Rice IT, (DVD), 2005-03-30 (Box 3)
  - Founders Room and Portraits; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-04 (Box 3)
  - Giant Nanotube Photos, (DVD), 2005-04 (Box 3)
  - David Leebron; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-04-01 (Box 3)
  - Y. Ping Sun; Bill Barnett Project, (DV), 2005-04-04 (Box 3)
  - Bert McMurtry, (DV), 2005-04-13 (Box 3)
  - Michael DeBakey PLS Cam #1 R1, (DV), 2005-04-15 (Box 3)
  - Michael DeBakey PLS Cam #3 R1, (DV), 2005-04-15 (Box 3)
  - Michael DeBakey PLS Cam #3 R2, (DV), 2005-04-15 (Box 3)
  - Ethnic Houston, Continuing Studies video, (DV), 2005-04-15 (Box 3)
  - Small is Big: Constructing the Guinness World Record Nanotube Model (5), Rice IT, (DVD), 2005-04-22 (Box 3)
  - Shepherd School Concert, (DVD), 2005-04-22 (Box 3)
  - Nanotube Guinness #1, (DV), 2005-04-22 (Box 3)
  - Nanotube Guinness #2, (DV), 2005-04-22 (Box 3)
  - Nanotube Guinness #3, (DV), 2005-04-22 (Box 3)
  - Honoring Bill and Peggy Barnett; Barnett retirement (3), (DVD), 2005-04-27 (Box 4)
  - Barnett video rough version, (DVD), 2005-04-27 (Box 3)
  - John Boles / History of Rice, (DV), 2005-05-03 (Box 3)
  - Graduation 2005 B-Roll, (DV), 2005-05-03 (Box 3)